solidtrustpay.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy - SolidTrust Pay

**The Privacy Policy below governs your SolidTrust Pay account and any information you provide on this site.**

 **Updated May 22, 2018**

A. Overview  
B. Information We Collect  
C. Our Use and Disclosure of Information  
D. Information Security  
E. Accessing and Changing Your Information  
F. Contacting Us

**  
_A. Overview_**  
In order to offer some of SolidTrust Pay's services and reduce fraud, SolidTrust Pay (SolidTrust Pay or "we") will ask you to provide information about yourself and your credit card and/or bank account. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect and how we use that information.

SolidTrust Pay takes the security of your personal information very seriously and will use your information only in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information or a list of our customers to third parties. However, as described in more detail in Part C below, there are limited circumstances in which some of your information will be shared with third parties, under strict restrictions, so it is important for you to review this Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy applies to all services that are hosted on the SolidTrust Pay website, whether SolidTrust Pay (or its subsidiaries or one of its affiliates) offers the services. By accepting the Privacy Policy and User Agreement in registration, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the SolidTrust Pay User Agreement

Your personal information will be stored and processed on our computers in Canada. The laws on holding personal data in Canada may be less stringent than the laws of your country, but SolidTrust Pay will hold and transmit your personal information in a safe, confidential and secure environment. If you object to your personal information being transferred or used as described in this Privacy Policy, please do not register for the SolidTrust Pay service.

**Notification of Changes**  
This policy may be revised over time as new features are added to the SolidTrust Pay service or as we incorporate suggestions from our customers. If we are going to use or disclose your personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time we collected the information, you will have a choice as to whether or not we use or disclose your information in this new manner. Any material changes will be effective only after we notify you via e-mail with at least 30 days notice of the amended Privacy Policy (if you have closed your SolidTrust Pay account, you will not be contacted and your personal information will not be used or disclosed in this new manner).

We will post the amended Privacy Policy prominently on our website so that you can always review what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Please check the SolidTrust Pay website at [SolidTrust Pay ](https://solidtrustpay.com/) at any time for the most current version of our Privacy Policy. 

Pages on the SolidTrust Pay website may include links to third party websites. SolidTrust Pay is not responsible for their operations, including but not limited to their information practices. Their privacy statements govern those sites. Users submitting information to or through these third party websites should review the privacy statement of these sites before providing them with personally identifiable information. 

__

**_B. Information We Collect_**

**Required Information**  
To open a SolidTrust Pay account, you must provide your name, company name (if any), address, phone number, and e-mail address. In order to make payments through SolidTrust Pay, you may, but are not required to, provide credit card, debit card or bank account information. We may also ask you to choose different security questions to answer. This required information may be necessary for us to process transactions, issue a new password if you forget or lose your password, protect you against credit card and checking account fraud, and to contact you should the need arise in administering your account. SolidTrust Pay only collects information that is required for the purposes that are stated in this policy. All information collected will be done so lawfully and not in excess. Information that has been submitted must be accurate, complete, and up-to-date.

If you choose to register or apply for certain optional features or products offered through the SolidTrust Pay website, you will be required to provide additional information to establish that you qualify for such features or products.

**Transaction Information**  
When you use SolidTrust Pay to send money to someone else or request money from someone else, we ask you to provide information related to each transaction, including the amount of the transaction and the username of the third party. We retain this information for each of your transactions through. We also collect the Internet address (IP address) of the computer or device you use to access your SolidTrust Pay account, in order to help detect possible instances of unauthorized transactions.

**Information About You From Third Parties**  
Specifically - for EU Citizens - upon opening an account you agree that:

In accordance with GDPR regulations, you authorize and permit Ecomm Link Ltd. (doing business as “www.solidtrustpay.com”) to:

  * store personal data (name, date of birth, occupation, email, address, telephone number(s), citizenship, National ID data (type, number, country of issue, expiry), IP address(es), and transaction history for the purposes of operating a SolidTrust Pay account 
  * send to your registered email payment and general account notifications 
  * send to your registered email marketing and promotion information, if you have opted in to receive such information 
  * share IP addresses with getipintel.net and IP-API.com for the purpose of location validation 
  * share any phone number listed on your account with OnVerify Ltd. adn whitepages.com for anti-fraud purposes 

In accordance with GDPR regulations, verification of your account means that you authorize and permit Answer Pro Services Inc. (a contracted administrative and business management provider for Ecomm Link Ltd) to:

  * receive, review, and store user-submitted documents (including, but not limited to, photo ID, passport, address documents [bills, bank statements], corporate registration documents, etc.) for the purpose of identity verification in compliance with International “Know Your Customer” regulations 
  * access personal data listed on user accounts with www.solidtrustpay.com for the purposes of customer support, anti-fraud monitoring and transaction processing 

You understand that you have the right to revoke any of the above permissions at any time, and you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Supervisory Authority of the European Union member state in which you reside. You can adjust your permissions at any time via the 'GDPR' section in the ‘Security’ area of your account.

In order to protect all our customers against potential fraud, we verify with third parties the information you provide. In the course of such verification, we receive personally identifiable information about you from such services. In particular, if you register a credit card or debit card with SolidTrust Pay, we may use card authorization and fraud screening services to verify that your card information and address matches the information that you supplied to SolidTrust Pay, and that the card has not been reported as lost or stolen. 

If you send or receive high overall payment volumes through SolidTrust Pay, in some circumstances we may conduct a background check on your business by obtaining information about you and your business from a credit bureau or a business information service. If you incur a debt to SolidTrust Pay, we will generally conduct a credit check on you by obtaining additional information about you from a credit bureau to the extent permitted by law. SolidTrust Pay, at its sole discretion, also reserves the right periodically to retrieve and review a business or consumer credit report for any account, and reserves the right to close an account based on information obtained during this credit review process.

**Additional Verification**  
If we cannot verify the information that you provide, or if you request a withdrawal by cheque to an address other than your verified physical address, we may ask you to send us additional information (such as your driver's license, credit card statement, and/or a recent utility bill or other information linking you to the applicable address), or to answer additional questions online or via phone to help verify your information.

**Website Traffic Information**  
Because of the way that Internet communication standards work, when you arrive at or leave the SolidTrust Pay website, we automatically receive the Internet address of the site that you came from or are going to. We also collect information on which pages of our website you visit while you are on the SolidTrust Pay site, the type of browser you use and the times you access our website. We may use this information only to try to understand our customer's preferences better and to manage the load on our servers, so as to improve our service and your experience with SolidTrust Pay. We do not track the websites that you visit before or after you leave the SolidTrust Pay site.

**Our Use of Cookies**  
Cookies are small files of data that reside on your computer and allow us to recognize you as a SolidTrust Pay customer if you return to the SolidTrust Pay site using the same computer and browser. We send a session cookie to your computer if and when you log in to your SolidTrust Pay account by entering your e-mail address and password. These cookies allow us to recognize you if you visit multiple pages in our site during the same session, so that you do not need to re-enter your password multiple times. Once you log out or close your browser, these session cookies expire and no longer have any effect.

In addition, we use cookies to process our referral program, described in Section C below. We may share cookie information regarding whether or not a certain user is already registered with SolidTrust Pay with certain merchants with whom we have an official co-marketing relationship.

**Customer Service Correspondence**  
If you correspond with us via phone, email, LiveChat or through the mail, we may retain such information in the records of your account. We may retain these records in order to measure and improve our customer service, and to investigate potential fraud and violations of our User Agreement. The Canadian Financial Regulatory Body (finTRAC) requires that records are maintained for a minimum of 5 years past the date of your last transaction or, if no transactions on record, the date of your original account creation. Canada Revenue Service requires the retention of data for a minimum period of 6 years. Our corporate document retention policy is 7 years or more as needed. We may, over time, delete these records if permitted by law. If you are an EU citizen, you may request that your account information be deleted; such a request will be completed after 7 years has passed since your last transacton or, if no transactions on record, the date of your original account creation.

**Questionnaires, Surveys and Profile Data**  
From time to time, we may offer optional questionnaires and surveys to our users for such purposes as collecting demographic information or assessing user interests and needs. The use of the information collected will be explained in detail in the survey itself. If we collect personally identifiable information from our users in these questionnaires and surveys, the users will be given notice of how the information will be used prior to their participation in the survey or questionnaire.

**_C. Our Use and Disclosure of Information_**

**Internal Uses**  
We collect, store and process your personal information on servers located in Europe. We use the information we collect about you in order to provide our services and process your transactions, to provide customer service, to determine your eligibility to receive offers for special features or products, and to improve our products and services. At your option (as indicated in your SolidTrust Pay user settings), we use the information you provide to access specific third party services on your behalf and perform the actions that you request us to perform.

We give access to individually identifiable information about our users only to those employees who require it to fulfill customer service requests.

**Disclosure to Other SolidTrust Pay Customers**  
If you are a registered SolidTrust Pay user, your name, e-mail address, account type and verification status may be displayed to other SolidTrust Pay customers whom you have paid or who are attempting to pay you through SolidTrust Pay. Your credit card number, bank account and other financial information will never be revealed to anyone whom you have paid or who has paid you through SolidTrust Pay, except if we are required to do so pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process.

If you are buying goods or services and paying through SolidTrust Pay, the seller of the goods or services may request that you provide a mailing address that SolidTrust Pay has confirmed as matching the billing address in the credit card system. You do not have to provide this information. If you do not provide the information, however, the seller may choose not to accept your SolidTrust Pay payment and not to complete the transaction.

SolidTrust Pay may also disclose to other SolidTrust Pay customers the number of payments you have received from Verified SolidTrust Pay customers (as defined in the User Agreement on the [SolidTrust Pay](http://solidtrustpay.com/) site), or other aggregate measures that provide an indication of your reputation with other SolidTrust Pay customers.

**Disclosure to Third Parties Other Than SolidTrust Pay Customers**  
SolidTrust Pay will NOT sell or rent any of your personally identifiable information to third parties. SolidTrust Pay will not share any of your personally identifiable information with third parties except in the limited circumstances described below, or with your express permission (and to other SolidTrust Pay customers as described above). These third parties are limited by law or by contract from using the information for secondary purposes beyond the purposes for which the information is shared. We share information with companies that help us process the transactions you request and protect our customer's transactions from fraud, such as sharing your credit card number with a service that screens for lost and stolen card numbers. See **Information About You From Third Parties** in Section B above. Additionally, if you go into a negative balance and owe us money, we may share information with processing companies including collection agencies.

We disclose the information we collect, as described in Section B above, to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These companies may be subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that prohibit using the information except to market the specified SolidTrust Pay related products or services, unless you have affirmatively agreed or given your prior permission for other uses.

We disclose information that we in good faith believe is appropriate to cooperate in investigations of fraud or other illegal activity, or to conduct investigations of violations of our User Agreement. Specifically, this means that if we conduct a fraud investigation and conclude that one side has engaged in deceptive practices, we can give that person or entity's contact information (but not bank account or credit card information) to victims who request it.

We disclose information in response to a subpoena, warrant, court order, levy, attachment, order of a court-appointed receiver or other comparable legal process, including subpoenas from private parties in a civil action.

We disclose information to your agent or legal representative (such as the holder of a power of attorney that you grant, or a guardian appointed for you.

We share aggregated statistical data with our business partners or for public relations. For example, we may disclose that a specific percentage of our users live in British Columbia. However, this aggregated information is not tied to personally identifiable information.

As with any other business, it is possible that SolidTrust Pay in the future could merge with or be acquired by another company. If such an acquisition occurs, the successor company would have access to the information maintained by SolidTrust Pay, including customer account information, but would continue to be bound by this Privacy Policy unless it is amended as described in Section A above.

We share your information with our parent, subsidiaries and joint ventures to help coordinate the services we provide to you, enforce our terms and conditions, and promote trust and safety.

**Our Contacts with SolidTrust Pay Customers**  
We communicate with users on a regular basis via e-mail to provide requested services, and we also communicate by phone to resolve customer complaints or investigate suspicious transactions. We use your e-mail address to confirm your opening of a SolidTrust Pay account, to send you notice of payments that you send or receive through SolidTrust Pay (including referral payments described below), to send information about important changes to our products and services, and to send notices and other disclosures required by law. Generally, users cannot opt out of these communications, but they will be primarily informational in nature rather than promotional.

We also may use your e-mail address to send you other types of communications that you can control, including tips, newsletters, customer surveys, and notice of special third-party promotions.

In connection with independent audits of our financial statements and operations, auditors may seek to contact a sample of our customers to confirm that our records are accurate. However, these auditors cannot use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**Internet Address Information**  
We use IP addresses, browser types and access times to analyze trends, administer the site, improve site performance and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**Your Use of Information and Our Services**  
In order to facilitate the transactions between SolidTrust Pay members, our service allows you limited access other user's contact information. As a seller you may have access to the User ID, email address and other contact information of the purchaser, and as a purchaser you may have access to the User ID, email address and other contact information of the seller.

By entering into our User Agreement, you agree that, with respect to other user's personally identifiable information that you obtain through the site or through an SolidTrust Pay-related communication or SolidTrust Pay-facilitated transaction, you will only use this information for: (a) SolidTrust Pay-related communications that are not unsolicited commercial messages, (b) using services offered through SolidTrust Pay, and (c) any other purpose that such user expressly agrees to after adequate disclosure of the purpose(s).

In all cases, you must provide users with the opportunity to remove themselves from your database and review any information you have collected about them. In addition, under no circumstances, except as defined in this Section, can you disclose personally identifiable information about another SolidTrust Pay user to any third party without our consent and the consent of such other user after adequate disclosure. Note that law enforcement personnel and other rights holders are given different rights with respect to information they access.

SolidTrust Pay does not tolerate unsolicited commercial e-mail (spam). Therefore, without limiting the foregoing, you may not add a SolidTrust Pay user to your mail list (e-mail or physical mail) without their express consent after adequate disclosure, even if said user has previously made a purchase from you. Our anti-spam policy is strictly enforced. To report SolidTrust Pay-related spam to SolidTrust Pay, please **contact us**.

**_D. Information Security_**

**Information Security**  
SolidTrust Pay handles your customer information with high standards of information security. Employees of SolidTrust Pay have received training to ensure the safety and security of your documents and privacy. We restrict access to your personally identifiable information to employees who need to know that information in order to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with national regulations to guard your non-public personal information. 

The security of your SolidTrust Pay account also relies on your protection of your SolidTrust Pay password. You should not share your SolidTrust Pay password with anyone. SolidTrust Pay representatives will never ask you for your password, so any e-mail or other communication requesting your password should be treated as unauthorized and suspicious. If you do share your SolidTrust Pay password with a third party for any reason, including third party promises of providing you additional services such as account aggregation, the third party will have access to your account and your personal information, and you may be responsible for actions taken using your password. If you believe someone else has obtained access to your password, please change it immediately by logging in to your account at SolidTrust Pay and changing your passwords via your **SECURITY** area. Contact us right away as described in Section F below.

**_E. Accessing and Changing Your Information_**

You can review the personal information you have provided us and make select changes to such information, or to the settings for your SolidTrust Pay account, at any time by logging into your account on the SolidTrust Pay website and accessing your MY PROFILE area. You can also close your account by contacting us. If you close your SolidTrust Pay account, we will mark your account in our database as SUSPENDED but will keep your account information in our database. This is necessary in order to deter fraud, by ensuring that persons who try to commit fraud will not be able to avoid detection simply by closing their account and opening a new account. However, if you close your account, your personally identifiable information will not be used by us for any further purposes, nor sold or shared with third parties, except as necessary to prevent fraud and assist law enforcement, or as required by law. Personal information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfilment of the purposes outlined in this policy.

**_F. Contacting Us_**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, you may contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO) directly via email to: privacy @ solidtrustpay.com; for questions regarding SolidTrust Pay's information practices, or your dealings with SolidTrust Pay, you are welcome to **contact us** via LiveChat/Ticket.
